<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>elliptic curve on Wise</title><link>https://wiseweb-works.github.io/blog/en/tags/elliptic-curve/</link><description>Recent content in elliptic curve on Wise</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wiseweb-works.github.io/blog/en/tags/elliptic-curve/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OpenVPN In-Depth Review</title><link>https://wiseweb-works.github.io/blog/en/post/openvpn-full-anlat%C4%B1m/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiseweb-works.github.io/blog/en/post/openvpn-full-anlat%C4%B1m/</guid><description>Introduction and Summary Today, we will make an in-depth review of OpenVPN, one of the most important software of recent times, in my opinion. In this review, we will first talk about what OpenVPN is used for. Then we will examine what we need to run the program and what needs to be done before the first run. Finally, I will try to explain what goes on in the background from the first moment the connection is started to the last step when the data is decrypted.</description></item><item><title>Generating ECC SSL Certificate on Linux Server</title><link>https://wiseweb-works.github.io/blog/en/post/ecc-ssl-sertifikas%C4%B1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiseweb-works.github.io/blog/en/post/ecc-ssl-sertifikas%C4%B1/</guid><description>Introduction and Summary Today we will learn how to generate SSL certificates to ensure that the traffic between a website or application server you manage and your visitors is confidential / reliable and verifiable. In my previous articles, I explained how and with what configuration you would deploy the certificate you produced. In this article, I will show you how to set up the equation of less bread, more meatballs, that is, how to produce a faster and more secure SSL certificate.</description></item></channel></rss>