<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>security on Wise</title><link>https://wiseweb.works/en/tags/security/</link><description>Recent content in security on Wise</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wiseweb.works/en/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OpenVPN In-Depth Review</title><link>https://wiseweb.works/en/post/openvpn-full-anlat%C4%B1m/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiseweb.works/en/post/openvpn-full-anlat%C4%B1m/</guid><description>Introduction and Summary Today, we will make an in-depth review of OpenVPN, one of the most important software of recent times, in my opinion. In this review, we will first talk about what OpenVPN is used for. Then we will examine what we need to run the program and what needs to be done before the first run. Finally, I will try to explain what goes on in the background from the first moment the connection is started to the last step when the data is decrypted.</description></item><item><title>Generating ECC SSL Certificate on Linux Server</title><link>https://wiseweb.works/en/post/ecc-ssl-sertifikas%C4%B1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiseweb.works/en/post/ecc-ssl-sertifikas%C4%B1/</guid><description>Introduction and Summary Today we will learn how to generate SSL certificates to ensure that the traffic between a website or application server you manage and your visitors is confidential / reliable and verifiable. In my previous articles, I explained how and with what configuration you would deploy the certificate you produced. In this article, I will show you how to set up the equation of less bread, more meatballs, that is, how to produce a faster and more secure SSL certificate.</description></item><item><title>Increasing SSL security on Linux Servers</title><link>https://wiseweb.works/en/post/ssl-konfigurasyonu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiseweb.works/en/post/ssl-konfigurasyonu/</guid><description>Increasing SSL security on Linux Servers Today, if you are serving a website and/or App on your current server, I will talk about the SSL connection you need and the openssl library in connection with it. SSL (Secure Socket Layer) and TLS (Transport Layer Security) are a form of connection that allows people who want to connect to your server to communicate securely with your site. There are versions ranging from SSL v1-v3 in the past, and while sites generally use these SSL versions, SSL has now been abandoned by the sites and has been replaced by the more secure TLS.</description></item><item><title>Increasing SSH security on Linux Servers</title><link>https://wiseweb.works/en/post/ssh-guvenligi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiseweb.works/en/post/ssh-guvenligi/</guid><description>Increasing SSH security on Linux Servers Today, I will talk about how we can keep the SSH service, which allows us to connect securely when you rent a server, more secure and away from malicious requests from outside. Foremost, I will describe the process under three different headings: simple, recommended and advanced. Title contents are gradually considered according to personal requirements. Although the titles are linked to each other, leaving them at a desired stage will not pose a problem.</description></item></channel></rss>